It's really important to look at your mental health and well-being when you're
working as a webcam model and there are some simple tips to help you to do that
.
Firstly, know your boundaries. So know what you're comfortable with doing and
what you're not comfortable with doing on cam and stick to it. You'll not
receive
any pressure from anybody to do anything that you don't want to do. If you feel
uncomfortable you can end a conversation whenever you like. You can kick
someone
out, you can block them. So just know that you always are in control, you
always
have the power. Play to your strengths whether you are creating an ulcer ego on
cam or whether you're being yourself. Use it as a time to experiment with
different looks, experiment with different things that you might like. Do
what feels good to you. This is about you. It's a time for exploration. It's a
time
to explore and have fun. Have a pre-cam routine or a ritual which enables you
to
come out of perhaps what might be an anxious mind back into your body, to
regulate and soothe yourself so you're ready to do a shift on cam. Just as an
actress or somebody who works in film might do, they have a little ritual
before they go on just a sense of themselves. So things that might help you
to do this are perhaps some mindful breathing so you can breathe slowly in
for a count of five, hold it for two at the top and then breathe out for a
count
of seven and that's just a bit of mindful breathing to sense yourself. You can
maybe use some positive self-talk or write down some mantras that you can
repeat to yourself before you go on cam as part of a little ritual. Don't
compare yourself to other people. We are all different and there's a reason
for that. Mainstream beauty ideals and what men actually want are two very
different things so bearing that in mind when you're on cam don't compare
yourself to other people. Your confidence will grow as you realise that
you are sexy in your own unique way and what you love or what you begin to love
about yourself will also be loved by other people. Release the stigma as women
we've been conditioned to feel shame around our bodies, around our
sexualities but we have a community here of strong empowered women that are
empowering each other. Release the stigma reach out to a community of cam
girls who are becoming empowered in what we do and you'll find that the
longer you're on cam the more you can embrace all parts of yourself the more
you can have financial freedom and be happy with who you are the more
confidence that you'll find. Speak to someone if you feel that you're
triggered on cam something happens you're not quite happy with or just in
general you don't feel great. Speak to either somebody else who understands or
speak to a professional and if you are a subscriber we do discounted counseling
.
I am a qualified counselor and reach out to us and we will guide you in the
direction of some help.